## **PONAGANTI SUDHEER**

Vizianagaram, Andhrapradesh India 535161 7036819736 | ponaganti.sudheer@gmail.com



## **Objective**

A Software engineer with the ideology of respect and love what you work on . Being fond of technology and learning new things and having an experience of 2 years in IT industry and specific about learning things in salesforce .Having so many dreams and commitments towards professional and personal career.

## Summary

2 years of experience in Salesforce CRM & Force.com platform.

Understanding of Salesforce native functionalities such as Apps, Objects, fields, users, roles, profiles, recordTypes,page layouts to support crucial business functions.

Understanding and implementing of Salesforce features like validation rules and Process Builder and Visual Flows.

Implementing security in Object level ,Field level, Record level with help of salesforce in built security features.

Development of UI with lightning webcomponents (LWC), Salesforce Lightning design system(SLDS).

Using Apex and SOQL to communicate with salesforce Database and third party APIs, Experience on deployment using GitLab and Jenkins.

## **Experience**

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

May 2021 - Present

Capgemini

Working as a Salesforce Developer for leading insurance client (StateFarm Insurance). Responsible for integrating multiple salesforce projects into the Master project and UI changes as well as functionality improvements using Salesforce LWC and Apex.

#### **Graduate Engineering Trainee**

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

Coromandel International Ltd

Worked as a production Engineer in a fertilizer manufacturing unit.

## **Projects**

Max Framework Project

Project Name: Max Framework

Company: Capgemini(May 2021 to Present)

Role: Salesforce Developer

Description: Worked on Insurance and Banking Project 'Max Framework' for the insurance client 'State Farm'

on development of Claims UI.

### Roles and Responsibilities:

### Programmatic Development

- 1. Responsible for designing LWC components which will host other components from different repositories as templates and communicating between them with LMS.
- 2. Implemented complex business requirements using Lightning web components, Apex Classes, Apex Test classes, Jest Classes, Apex Triggers, Lightning Data Service, Lightning Message Service.

### Declarative Development

- 1. Performed migration of projects as packages between different Salesforce orgs using Gitlab.
- 2. Worked on Administrative part of Salesforce on standard objects, custom objects, Fields, Record types, Page Layouts, Reports, Profiles, Permission sets, validation rules as per the requirement.
- 3. Worked on production releases and creation of Technical checkout and Business checkout Documentation.

Provided project Code walk through to new resources to team and also provided internal Salesforce Apex,LWC,Jest training to junior developers.

#### Max Manage Task

Project Name: Max Manage Task

Roles and Responsibilities:

Responsible for Designing the Manage Task Ui,

Worked on Apex to make an Api connection and use the data in the Ui with help of JavaScript wire methodology. Responsible for developing reusable components. The project is having four LWC components which will help to see Tasks linked to a particular claim. Users can access all the tasks when they open the claim tab.

### Memory Game Project

This is a Sample Realtime Project . This is Created on Top of Salesforce Resources and using Salesforce Lightning Design System and Lightning Web Components. The Ui is Developed using HTML and CSS and the Logic is Build using JavaScript.

GithubUrl: https://github.com/sudheerponaganti/MemoryGame

### **Employee Information**

Employee Information is a simple application , which will contain Employee Name and Id , Skills Whenever we select an Id from the drop down list , It will automatically take the skills attached to that Id. This Application is Developed using Salesforce LWC and Apex

### **Attendance Management Application**

Role: Team Member

### Project Information:

Attendance Management application is specially developed to help college staff to manage and maintain records of Admin and Faculty and Students and their respective Courses and Subjects in the college will useful to Add Attendance to Students

**Environment**: Spring Tool Suite: 4.10.0

PostgreSQL

**Hibernate**: 5.4.21

**JDK**: 1.8

Language: Java

### Skills

SFDC Programmatic : Lightning Web Components, Apex, SOQL, Apex Triggers, Governor Limits, Apex Testing and Debugging, Apex API callouts.

SFDC Declarative: Objects, Tabs, Profiles, Permissionsets, Record Types, Page Layouts, Security in Salesforce, Reports, Dashboards, Debugging logs.

Other Skills: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Java

## **Tools**

Vscode

Gitlab

**Jenkins** 

## Certifications

Salesforce Certified Platform Developer-1(PD1)

Salesforce Certified Administrator(SCA)

Salesforce Certified JavaScript Developer-1

Salesforce Certified Financial Services Cloud Accredited Professional

Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder

# **Achievements & Awards**

A-Plus Certified Professional from Capgemini.

star awardee for the H2-2022.

## Education

Course / Degree	School / University	Grade / Score	Year
Bachelor of Technology Chemical Engineering	Andhra University	8.55	2016 to 2020
Intermediate MPC	Sri Chaitanya Jr college Marikivalasa	96%	2014 to 2016
Schooling	MJPAPBCWRES School Simhachalam	9.5	2008 to 2014
Languages			
Telugu			
English			
Hindi			